Avinash Tingre

Software Engineer with 5 years of extensive experience implementing large back-end systems. Passionate about innovation, efficiency, and automation. Recognized for team work and technical capability.

tingre.avinash@gmail.com > +91-7741920226 \ LinkedIn/tingreavinash in GitHub/tingreavinash () https://tingreavinash.github.io ()

EXPERIENCE

Opus Pune, MH

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2022 - Present

- Developed framework for Audit Logging, which lead to intercept every API request in available micro-services.
- Streamlined features related to Software Security Framework (SSF) such as **Data Encryption**, Data Masking as per the user permissions.
- Implemented **Event Logging** framework which is used in all micro-services, it is used to raise events for important user actions, it supports explicit as well as implicit event logging mechanism.
- Awarded with "Spot Award" for quality of work.
- Developed secure application modules using code analysis tool like SonarQube / SonarLint.

Cerence Pune, MH

Software Engineer

May 2021 - Feb 2022

- Built data extraction utility which takes chunks of data from JSON document and stores it in Spreadsheet.
- Developed features in the Natural Language Processing Server (NLPS) following an Agile Scrum process.

Netcracker Pune, MH

Software Engineer

Mar 2021 - May 2021

- Agile development using Jira, Jenkins, SVN.
- Worked with the senior software developer to understand the product and technologies used.

Amdocs Pune, MH

Software Developer

Oct 2017 - Feb 2021

- Developed a **RESTful web service** to handle data transmission between in-house application and DNS management application for registering DNS addresses.
- Streamlined and automated the deployment task on Linux using Ansible and shell script.
- Awarded with "Spot Award" by manager for outperforming the critical tasks.

PROJECTS

Hotfix Search Application

- Conceptualized and developed a web application to explore historical hotfixes provided over a period.
- It helped in achieving a 90% reduction in efforts for manual tasks.

Leave Management System

• Created an application to manage the employee leaves. Streamlined the logging process. Which has resulted in 70% increased efficiency to track the historic leaves.

Hotfix Download Utility

- Reduced 50% efforts by creating a web application to download a set of hotfixes from Windows NFS.
- Using this tool users can download set of hotfixes in a click. It is used by specific teams in Amdocs.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Oracle SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Spring AOP, JPA, Angular

Technologies: AWS, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Maven, Micro-services

Tools and Other: Jira, JUnit, Mockito, Data Structures, Algorithms, UNIX, Shell Scripting, Tomcat, WebLogic, Log4j

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Savitribai Phule Pune University - 2017